ICC Health Advantage Industries
is one of the best health insurance plans in which, along with normal tax, we
also get the option of maternity. In today's
video, we will completely review this plan and
learn about its
features and benefits. So stay tuned to the
video and let's talk about
some of the unique benefits of this plan,
such as worldwide tax. If
your contribution is above Rs 25 lakh, then
in this plan you also
get the option of worldwide tax. Along with this,
you can take tele consultation from the company's network medical
consultation
for any of your medical queries. Along with this,
you also get the option of ambulance.
Apart from this,
you also get some discount on maternity tax and vaccines.
Talking about the eligibility criteria for this plan, the minimum entry age for an adult is
18 years. The
maximum entry age for an adult
is 65 years and for a dependent child is 25
years. After that, they can be
shifted to an individual policy.  In this plan,
we get the option of live long renewal. The
minimum age of proposal is 18 years.
Talking about the policy term, in this policy also
we get the options of 1 year, 2 years and 3 years.
In this plan, along with individual, we
also get the option of family floater,
for which two adults and three
children will be available. The relations on the family floor include
grandfather,
grandmother, father in doctor, mother in doctor, father
in doctor
and brother in doctor
are available. In-patient treatment means that
for any hospital stay above 24 hours, charges up to Rs. 1000 will be
available. There is no camping for hospital accommodation. You
can take a room of any category
for which charges up to Rs. 1000
are available. IU treatment means
Ayurveda i.e. Siddha Homeopathy. The charges for
any in-patient treatment related to these treatments will be Rs. 1000.
Apart from this,
charges for 60 and 180 days will be available for pre- and post-hospitalization.
Meaning of pre-hospitalization  It
happens that
for the medical expenses incurred before hospitalization, it will be for 60 days and
post hospitalization, that is,
after discharge from the hospital, our medical
expenses will be for 18 days. There is no
list of procedures.
Treatment means such
treatments which, due to advancement of technology, do not require
long hospitalization.
These are not procedures of a few hours,
like cataract
surgery, hernia, etc. The surgeries that are there are included
in the list of emergency care procedures,
they will also be listed in front of you.
Apart from this, there are a lot of expenses in the case of organ transplant of the
donor,
that too. If we talk about UPTO benefits, then
first is ambulance tax, for which
you will be
available a charge of one percent. Next
benefit is animal pet, for which you will be
available a charge of up to 10,000.
Next benefit is the benefit of restoration,
which we
also know by the name of Statement Rifle Vichar or Restor. This means that
If in any year your basic sum assured gets exhausted due to
hospitalization, then the
insurance company
refills your policy for that period for
any further hospitalization in the year,
whether it is for you or for any other
injured member in your policy. Also,
you can avail this restore benefit for the
illness for which
you have already taken hospitalization
because earlier in some policies, there was a clause that if you get treatment from the day before,
you will not get the restore benefit for it.
In this plan, instead of no claim bonus, we get
guaranteed cumulative bonus which is
20% off and the maximum will now be available up to 200%.
This means that
if we had
taken any claim on no claim, it would have been reduced,
but this cumulative bonus will
not be reduced once it is exhausted.
In this plan, we get the option of annual health up,
for which you get 5% off and up
to Rs. 10,000.  Charges of Rs. 1000 will be available on a cashless
basis. Along with this, the benefit of domicile hospital is
that if a patient's condition is so
critical that he cannot be taken to the hospital
or there is no bed available in any nearby hospital
and in such a time when we do
treatment at home or hospitalization at home, then it is
called domestic hospitalization. This will also be available to us. Along with this, the
next benefit is surgery
variety surgeries which we get done to
reduce obesity,
they will also be available for 50% off time.
Along with this, we get covalence benefit, which
means that if our hospitalization is more than 10 days, then the
company
provides us a lump sum benefit of Rs. 20,000. Let us now
talk about some optional benefits of this plan.
First, there is an important optional benefit
which is also a part of the plan.
Maternity tax has three parts: maternity
benefit, newborn tax, and
10% for vaccination maternity tax.  These will be
available, which will be maximum up to 10
lakhs. Meaning that if you have a
policy of 10 lakhs, then you will be
available up to ₹1 lakh for maternity.
Double the maternity benefit for newborn baby will be available, which means
if your maternity benefit is ₹1 lakh, then up
to ₹2 lakhs will be available for newborn baby.
Along with this, a
charge of one percent will be available on vaccination for newborn baby in the first year,
which will be maximum up
to ₹10,000. If
you take this rider, then if
you detect any of the listed critical illnesses, then a
short cut looms up pay out in front of you.
Apart from this, the next rider is the
charge for personal accident, which includes accidental death,
permanent total disability and permanent
partial disability. The next rider
is sum injured protector. The meaning of this rider is  The next rider is that
our insurance policy increases according to inflation. The insurance policy
adjusts with inflation. The
next rider is claim protector, which is a
normal health insurance policy.
Many consumable and non-medical charges are
not covered under this
policy. The charges in
our hospital bills can sometimes be up to
10-15-20%. So this is a
very good rider which we should provide
with our policy.
In this plan of waiting periods, the initial waiting period is
30 days. The waiting period for free existing diseases is
2 years. For re-existing diseases, that is, the
diseases which we already have
before taking the policy, apart from this, there is a
fee waiting period of 2 years. For specific diseases, that is,
slow-
growing diseases which develop gradually and do
not require immediate treatment,
such as hernia and cataract, there is a waiting period of 2 years for these,
which is
common throughout the industry. Apart from this, for critical
illnesses, there is a waiting period of 2 years.  The
survival period for this is zero days, which is
a very good feature. The survival
period means that you will
get the critical payment only if the policyholder survives
till the survival period after the critical diagnosis.
If the
policyholder dies before the survival period, however, there is
no survival period in this rider. Apart from this, there will be a
waiting period of 3 years for breast cancer surgery.
In this plan, we get some valuable IT
services like gym, video and
teleconsultation, telemedicine, pharmacy and
diagnostic services, online chat with
doctor, doctor on call and health assistant
services.
In this plan, we get zone-based premium
which is divided into three zones.
Ghaziabad, Noida, Muzaffarnagar, Alwar, Bharatpur
and the entire Delhi NCR region are
included. Apart from this, Mumbai, Thane district, Navi
Mumbai, whole Gujarat state and Kolkata will all
come in zone one. Zone two includes Hyderabad,
Chhattisgarh, Madhya Pradesh, Daman and Diu, Dadar and
Nagar Haveli, Goa, Maharashtra excluding
Mumbai and Thane district, Navi Mumbai.
In Zone 3, the Rest of India
policy discount is available. This means that if we
buy a two-year policy together, we
get a 7.5% discount on the premium.
If we buy a three-year policy together,
we get a 10% discount. Additionally,
we get a soft copy discount of ₹100.
If we
don't select a hard copy and just buy a copy of
our policy, we get a ₹100
discount, which is very
good.
Nowadays, everything is happening online, so we do
n't need a hard copy as much.
Friends, this was about the ICC Health
Advantage plan. If
you have any doubts regarding this plan, you
can ask by commenting below.
Therefore, it is very important that you
do a good analysis or
purchase health insurance by taking advice from an expert.
If you want to be successful
in buying health insurance, you
can take our help by WhatsApping the number given below. Friends, if you liked this video, then
definitely like it and
subscribe to the channel. See you
in the next video. Thank you.